Guide to the Yale New Haven Educational Corporation Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale New Haven Educational Corporation records
1967-1970
RU 949
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2.75
The records consist of correspondence, applications for licensing and funding, agreements, and meeting minutes documenting the Yale New Haven Educational Corporation (YNHEC) and its unsuccessful attempt to establish an education television station in New Haven, Connecticut.
Yale New Haven Educational Corp
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 4-C (YRG 4-C), records documenting public information functions of Yale University.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from the Office of Public Affairs, 1980.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The records are arranged alphabetically by subject.
Biographical / Historical
The Yale New Haven Educational Corporation (YNHEC) was established at Yale in 1967. The Board of Directors included as president, Howard Weaver (associate secretary of Yale University), treasurer, John Ecklund (treasurer of Yale University), and secretary, David Walker (editor of Yale Reports) as well as prominent individuals in the New Haven community. Its purpose was to design, produce, and distribute programs to benefit Yale University and the general public. Additionally, the corporation wanted to build and operate an educational television station in New Haven, Connecticut. Unable to secure funding for the project, the YNHEC dissolved in 1970.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, applications for licensing and funding, agreements, and meeting minutes documenting the Yale New Haven Educational Corporation (YNHEC) and its unsuccessful attempt to establish an education television station in New Haven, Connecticut.
Educational television stations; Television in education; Yale New Haven Educational Corp; Yale University -- Public relations; Yale University. Office of Public Affairs
- Records, Series I
  - Applications
    - General
      - Education Survey, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Facilities, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Financial, 1962-1969 (Box 1, Folder 3 - 4)
      - Telephone Survey, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Federal Communications Commission, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 6 - 9)
    - Health, Education, & Welfare
      - Application, 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 10 - 12)
      - Evaluation, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Follow Up, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 14 - 15)
      - Follow Up, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 16 - 17)
      - Legal, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - New Haven, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 19 - 22)
      - State/Federal, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 23 - 24)
    - WGBH
      - Application, 1967-1969 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - Programming, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - Support, 1966-1970 (Box 2, Folder 27 - 28)
  - Bills and requisitions, 1967-1969 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Board of directors, 1967-1969 (Box 3, Folder 30 - 32)
  - Construction
    - General, 1966-1969 (Box 3, Folder 33 - 34)
    - York University, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Contracts (Agreements), 1968-1970 (Box 3, Folder 36 - 37)
  - Correspondence
    - 1964-1968 (Box 3, Folder 38 - 42)
    - 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 43 - 55)
    - 1970 (Box 5, Folder 56 - 61)
  - Insurance, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Legal
    - General, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 63 - 64)
    - New Haven, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Lourda decisions, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Meetings
    - Annual, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - Third, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - Fourth, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 69 - 70)
  - Politicans, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - Speech, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Support letters, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - University of Connecticut, 1967-1969 (Box 6, Folder 74 - 75)
  - WYNH, Channel 65 report, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - Miscellaneous, 1967-1969 (Box 6, Folder 77 - 78)